hey everyone welcome back to the store
automation playlist and we are talking
about the top 10 Tosca best practices
now this is the last of the best
practice uh which is the 10th best
practice and before this we have done
almost all the nine best practices so if
you have not watched them please go
ahead and watch them in our playlist
also please subscribe to our channel so
that you don't miss out on all the
upcoming videos
now let's talk about this particular
best practice it is the last best
practice and also it is the most
important best practice because it is
going to take care of lot of other
things
it talks about implementing a review
process in your project
now why it is important
now no matter if you work in a
development team or a testing team
every test case which is written by the
tester or every code change which is
done by a developer goes through some or
the other review process
now there are static code review tools
available with the development team also
there are senior developers or senior
testers who review each other's work
right
and this is done because uh you need to
have another person looking at your work
because you might not uh come across all
the different improvements which will be
suggested by somebody else looking at
your code or looking at your test cases
right so you might not cover everything
in the first instance so you need to
take it through uh your peer reviews so
that you can get the best out of your
code or your test case right
and during this process they need to
follow some best practices right so all
the best practices which we have
discussed and lot more so they will keep
and keep an eye on all of these best
practices when they are looking at your
uh test cases or your modules uh
specifically talking about Tosca right
now what you should do in Tosca is you
should Implement a robust review process
for all the artifacts no matter if it is
a test case if it is a module even you
can do it for requirements uh if they
are created in your project they should
all go through this particular review
process
also it should be based on certain
approval stages and the four eyes
principle
now what is the four eyes principle
right so this principle is applied in a
review process where every change is uh
monitored by two persons or reviewed by
two persons right so that's why there
are four eyes looking at your code
change or any other change right and it
needs to go through their approval and
their review before
um it is finalized and you can think
that okay this is the final version of
my code or my test case right so that's
the 4i check which we should do uh
during this whole review process and it
should go through different approval
stages right
now let's see what are these approval
stages and how you can implement this
review process within Tosca
so um the process is pretty simple right
uh mostly you would like to implement
the review process for your modules and
test cases because here uh people will
make mistakes like
um people might create duplicate modules
or uh they may not be using the right
structure or they mean they may be using
lots of module attributes so we have
talked about so many best practices
around this right and you can put
together a process where you can review
all of this before it is like in the
completed stage right
so the approval stages are they are
basically three approval stages this is
recommended by tracing this obviously
you can put more stages if you like but
the three are the recommended ones so
the first stage should be the inbox
Stitch so this is where uh you or
somebody else will put or create the
modules and start working on those
modules right so this uh here all these
modules are currently in progress or in
bug right so they have not been
completed
once you think that you have completed
your work okay
then you can move these modules into the
ready for approval stage okay and once
it reaches this ready for approval stage
then the approver or the reviewer will
come here and he will go through this
all these modules or test cases right
and once it thinks that everything is as
per the expectations it is following the
best practices then this will be
approved and it will be ready to move
into the completed stage
so this completed stage should be your
final modules which should be used in
your project okay
and once uh the modules are moved into
completed you can very well delete it
from the other folders okay so that you
don't create duplicate modules and you
maintain the structure and also all the
different modules which are flowing
through these three approval stages
right
now you can put two reviewers so that
you can complete the 4i check right and
they will look at all the modules which
are in this particular approval stage
and then once their proof it should be
moved to completed okay and then
um whatever is moved you can remove it
from the other folders
same thing can be done for the test
cases section okay you can have a
completed and a ready for approval and a
in work stage or folders and then
um once you start working on it you can
keep it in in work then you can move it
to ready for approval once it is
approved and reviewed then you move it
to complete it okay
so this will keep a check on all the
test cases all the modules which are
being created in your project
and since it is going through so many
checks and reviews you will produce the
best or possible test cases or modules
which are efficient and which are
following the best practices okay the
same thing you can do for requirements
but requirements anyways you will be
talking to your business owners or the
product owners so there is less chances
of uh making any mistakes in the
requirements rather than
doing it for modules or test cases
because requirements will be either
taken care by a particular person or you
will probably use a document to create
all these requirements but the same
approval process can also be followed
for requirements okay
and even execution so execution anyway
you will execute your test cases so this
I think doesn't require any approval or
review process but still if you want you
can do the same okay so it can be uh
done as I said for each and every
artifact you create uh in your Tosca
project
it should go through all the different
approval stages it should be reviewed
properly and it should follow the four I
check okay so these are the
recommendations by transientists and
this will make sure that all the best
practices which you have been discussing
about are being followed in your project
and this way you will make sure your
test cases are as efficient or your
modules are as efficient as possible and
you don't have any performance issues
um you don't have any workspace size
issues uh you don't have a lot of
Maintenance as your maintenance efforts
will go down because of this and there
will be an overall review process which
will be followed across the team okay so
everybody will be following this and
then this could be formed into
guidelines which can be followed by any
new member who is joining the team as
well right so that's all for this
particular video I hope you enjoyed it
and you learned something new today
there are lots of other best practices
which we haven't discussed here but I
will leave the links in the description
so that you can go through all the best
practices and you should follow them
When developing any artifacts in your
Tosca project there are lots more videos
coming up in Tosca so keep watching uh
out for more videos in our Channel and
do support us by uh sharing it across
with your team members or your friends
until we talk again uh keep watching and
keep learning